jobg8.com 2018-12-28

# Jobg8 - Privacy Policy

### 1 Introduction

#### 1.1 Definition of Terms

“Candidate” is an individual who is using one of Jobg8’s services via a third party and whom Jobg8 do not have a direct relationship. For example, a job seeker.

“Customer” is a direct business relationship, whom are interested in and or using one or more of Jobg8’s services. For example, a Job Board.

#### 1.2 Who We Are and What We Do

Jobg8 Limited (“Jobg8”) is an online global marketplace for buying and selling qualified Job Applications, Job Seeker Traffic and Jobs. We are the world’s largest job board network. Jobg8 supplies high quality vacancies and pre-qualified applicants to job boards that deliver revenue. Since 2008, we have established our reputation as the ultimate job board resource – by growing our clients’ brands, not competing against them.

Jobg8 Limited (“Jobg8”) is committed to preserving the privacy of all data passed to or processed by Jobg8, or through www.jobg8.com or www.jobg8alerts.com (either to be known as “the site”).

#### 1.3 Data Controller / Data Processor

Jobg8 are a Data Processor working on behalf of the Data Controllers (our customers). Jobg8 process the data as per the agreements drawn up between the two parties.

For the Job Alerts services, Jobg8 will act as a Joint Data Controller as well as a Processor, providing the data to a third party for further processing.

#### 1.4 Consent

Where Jobg8 acts as the Data Processor, the consent for processing will reside with the customer that the candidate has registered with.

For the Job Alerts service, even though Jobg8 is a Joint Controller and Processor, the consent will reside with the customer that the candidate has registered with.

For marketing, Jobg8 has a contract with current and new clients that allows Jobg8 to contact customers to update them on new services and other marketing functions.

#### 1.5 Data Protection Officer (DPO)

Jobg8 have designated a member of staff to act as the Data Protection Officer, to contact them please use the email address – [dpo@jobg8.com](mailto:dpo@jobg8.com)

#### 1.6 Changes to Privacy Policy

Any changes to our privacy policy in the future will be posted to the site and where appropriate through email notification. The latest revision date for this policy is 24th May 2018.

#### 1.7 Know Your Rights

For full details of your rights and the latest data protection regulations please refer to the Information Commissioner’s Office website: <https://ico.org.uk/>

### 2 Data We Collect

#### 2.1 General

The data we collect depends on our services used and is essential to our ability to provide such services. All data collected is for a legitimate business interests whilst minimising any impact on privacy.

We may collect data about your usage of our Site (see Google Analytics), as well as data about you from emails or letters you send to us.

Jobg8 reserves the right to retain data that you have requested be deleted where there is a legitimate legal reason why such data should be retained by Jobg8.

#### 2.2 From Candidates

The majority of candidate data collected by Jobg8 is supplied directly via our customers with which the candidate are registered. For some services we do collect personal data directly from the candidate; for instance, when Jobg8 host the job application form on behalf of the customer.

In all cases we collect the minimum amount of personal data required from the candidate to help assist with job seeking. This generally includes but is not limited to; name, email address, phone number, residential address, IP address and curriculum vitae / resume.

Other non-personal candidate data can be collected, relating to job seeking activity; for example, job application history or an expression of interest in a CV review service.

#### 2.3 From Customers

Business level data will be collected from our customers, which will include some personal contact data. This data will enable us to provide you with access to all parts of our Site and to supply our services, which also includes contacting you. By signing up with Jobg8 you agree to be contacted by our customer services function to manage your account.

In particular, we may use your data to contact you for your views on our services and to notify you occasionally about important changes or developments to the Site or our services. Furthermore, where you have consented, we might also use your data to contact you about other services Jobg8 offer that may be of interest to you by post, telephone, fax or email.

For technical integrations we may be required to collect and store access credentials to your services.

#### 2.3.1 Credit Cards

We do not store full credit card details nor do we share personal data where consent is not granted.

Online payments to Jobg8 can be made via credit card. Jobg8 does not hold the full credit card details; our third party vendor (Stripe) holds this data. The data that is stored by Jobg8 is as follows:  
Name, last four digits of the credit card, expiry date, type of card (debit, credit), brand (MasterCard, visa, etc.)

Stipes privacy policy can be reviewed via <https://stripe.com/gb/privacy>

#### 2.4 Telephone Calls

We record all telephone calls to assist in dealing with your enquiry and for training and security purposes. The call recordings will be retained for up to 90 days.

### 3 Use of Data

#### 3.1 General

The data that you provide to us will be stored on computers solely owned by Jobg8 Limited and its group companies.

Your data may be accessed by our staff working within and outside England, third party companies whom we may use to provide part of our services and whom may be located outside England. We may also pass aggregated statistical data on the usage of our Site to third parties, but this will not include data that can be used to identify you.

Under no circumstance will we pass your data to third parties to enable them to contact you themselves about products and services which they offer, without your consent.

If our business enters into a joint venture or is sold, transferred or merged with another business entity, your data may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners, but your data will continue to be only used for what you have consented it for.

Unless required to do so by law, we will not share, sell or distribute any of the data you provide to us, without your consent.

Any personal data written on paper will be shredded at the end of the working day.

#### 3.2 Candidates

If you are searching for work, we will assist you in your job seeking. Our service connects job seekers and employers across the global. As part of our service we will collect and process your job application and deliver it to the advertiser.

We will also work with Job Boards to which you are already registered to keep them informed of your current job seeking activity.

If you are looking for additional services such as training courses or CV reviews we will assist you appropriately. As part of our services we will process your request and deliver it to the applicable provider.

We also work on behalf of various third party organisations to which you are registered to provide a Job Alerts Service. This will provide a regular email of current job advertisements based on your job seeking criteria. This email will provide an unsubscribe link should you wish to stop the emails or contact the third party website to which you are registered. The third party website can be found at the top of your job alert emails.

#### 3.2.1 Retention of Data

The retention of candidate data is service specific, however for all services we store data for the minimum period necessary to successfully provide the service. After which candidate data is permanently removed from our live systems.

#### 3.2.2 Right to be Forgotten

To exercise your right to be forgotten, please contact the data controller you originally registered with. You can also exercise you right to be forgotten by Jobg8 by using Contact Us

#### 3.2.3 Portability

If you require your data to be moved, please contact the data controller you originally registered with.

#### 3.3 Customers

We are the sole owners of business level data collected from our customers. We only have access to collect data that you voluntarily give us via email or other direct contact from you. We will not sell or rent this data to anyone. We retain all customer data indefinitely.

No emails that contain passwords will be sent to you, if your account needs a password reset, then you can request a reset link via our website.

#### 3.3.1 Customer Relationship Management System

Jobg8 uses Salesforce as their CRM system to store, manage and report on customer data. To review their privacy policy please visit <https://www.salesforce.com/uk/company/privacy/>

#### 3.3.2 Marketing

Our email marketing is permission based. If you received a mailing from us, our records indicate that (a) you have expressly shared this address for the purpose of receiving data in the future ("opt-in"), or (b) you have registered or purchased or otherwise have an existing relationship with us.

Each email sent contains an easy, automated way for you to cease receiving email from us, or to change your expressed interests. If you wish to do this, simply follow the ‘Unsubscribe’ link or ‘Update Preferences’ at the end of any email.

#### 3.3.3 Right to be Forgotten

If you change your mind about being contacted by Jobg8 and would like personal data deleted please Contact Us and provide details of your request.

### 4 Cookies

Cookies are small amounts of data, which we store on your computer and are essential for proper use of the Jobg8 sites. Our system will issue cookies to your computer when you log on to the site. Cookies make it easier for you to log on and use the site during future visits. They also allow us to monitor website traffic and to personalise the content of the site for you. You may set up your computer to reject cookies although, in this case, you may not be able to use our site to its full capabilities. For further details, please refer to our Cookies Policy

### 5 Links to Other Websites

This privacy notice does not cover the links within this site linking to other websites. We encourage you to read the privacy statements on the other websites you visit.

### 6 Complaints

If you are not satisfied with the way that Jobg8 has processed/used your data, you have the right to complain to the supervisory authority. For Jobg8 this supervisory authority is the “Information Commissioner’s Office”. Their link is <https://ico.org.uk/>

### 7 Accessing your Data

You are entitled to see the data held about you and ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that it is accurate and kept up to date. If you wish to do this, please Contact Us with your request.

Where the request is to see data that is held by Jobg8, proof of your identity will be required. Once the proof provided (passport, utility bill etc.,) has been checked, your documents (paper or electronic) will be destroyed, and the requested data will be sent. Jobg8 are committed to providing this data to you within 30 days of receiving your proof of identity. The copy of the data will be provided free of charge. However, there will be a charge of £10 when a request is manifestly unfounded or excessive, particularly if it is repetitive. The fee is based on the administrative cost of providing the data.

### 8 Data Backups

Data is backed up regularly and stored securely offline. The data in these backups will not be altered as part of any requested data changes in the live systems. In the unlikely event of a backup being restored a data backup policy is in place to retrospectively apply any requested data changes.

### 9 Security

Our website and servers are scanned on a regular basis for security holes and known vulnerabilities in order to make your visit to our site as safe as possible.

We use regular Malware Scanning and apply the latest security software updates from Microsoft. All Jobg8 and group companies PC’s have virus checking software installed which is updated on a regular basis.

Your personal data is contained behind secured networks and is only accessible by a limited number of persons who have special access rights to such systems, and are required to keep the data confidential. In addition, all sensitive/credit data you supply is encrypted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology.

### 10 Contact Us

All comments, queries and requests relating to our use of your data are welcomed. Please Contact Us with any feedback.

We will also monitor any emails sent to us, including file attachments, for viruses or malicious software. Please be aware that you have a responsibility to ensure that any email you send is within the bounds of the law.
